// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Climate is:",
    answer: "The weather pattern in a particular territory over a period of many years",
    options: [
      "The state of the weather in the course of a week",
      "A feature of the weather specifying the frequency of precipitation",
      "The weather pattern in a particular territory over a period of many years",
      "What old people remember about weather patterns, weather lore"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Since the middle of the 19th century the air temperature on Earth",
    answer: "Has risen",
    options: [
      "Has risen",
      "Has not changed",
      "Has fallen",
      "Rose sharply and then fell again"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of these features is not relevant to climate?",
    answer: "Longitude",
    options: [
      "The pattern of precipitation",
      "Longitude",
      "Dominant winds",
      "–êir temperature"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "What do we call a scientist who studies weather and climate?",
    answer: "meteorologist",
    options: [
      "speleologist",
      "geologist",
      "meteorologist",
      "seismologists"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following phenomena is not considered to be a consequence of climate change?",
    answer: "Earthquakes",
    options: [
      "Earthquakes",
      "Droughts",
      "Rising ocean levels",
      "Tornadoes"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 6,
    question: "What can you do to help fight climate change?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "Divest from fossil fuel companies",
      "Engage yourself in the science behind climate change",
      "Vote for political candidates who will advocate for climate-related legislation and policy improvements",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What gases are causing current climate change?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "Methane",
      "Carbon Dioxide",
      "Nitrous Oxide",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following climatic zones has wet and hot weather conditions all year round?",
    answer: "Tropical",
    options: [
      "Tropical",
      "Sub-Tropical",
      "Equatorial",
      "Temperate"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which climatic zone is characterized by high air temperature and much precipitation, falling evenly through the year?",
    answer: "Equatorial",
    options: [
      "Tropical",
      "Sub-Tropical",
      "Sub-Equatorial",
      "Equatorial"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which of the following factors has only short-term impact on climate (a few years or decade)?",
    answer: "Volcanic eruptions",
    options: [
      "Change in the tilt of the Earth's axis",
      "Continental drift",
      "Human emissions of greenhouse gases",
      "Volcanic eruptions"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 11,
    question: "As the climate becomes warmer, the level of the world ocean:",
    answer: "Rises",
    options: [
      "Remains unchanged",
      "Rises",
      "Falls",
      "Cannot be predicted"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Where is climate warming happening the fastest?",
    answer: "In the Arctic",
    options: [
      "In Southern Europe",
      "In tropical latitudes",
      "In the Arctic",
      "In the Southern Hemisphere"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 13,
    question: "The most obvious sign of climate change in mountain regions is:",
    answer: "The melting of glaciers",
    options: [
      "The melting of glaciers",
      "Increase of windy days",
      "Drying up of mountain rivers",
      "Reduction of precipitation"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 14,
    question: "In some parts of the world, rainstorms have become more intense over the past several decades. Is that a change in weather or climate?",
    answer: "Climate",
    options: [
      "Weather",
      "Climate",
      "Both",
      "Cannot be predicted"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Which of the following control is not affecting the climate of India?",
    answer: "Cyclones",
    options: [
      "Altitude",
      "Cyclones",
      "Latitude",
      "Pressure & Winds"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Uttar Pradesh's climate can be reffered as ______",
    answer: "Humid Sub-Tropical Climate",
    options: [
      "Humid Sub-Tropical Climate",
      "Temperate Climate",
      "Dry Climate",
      "Tropical Wet Climate"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Steppe climate is found in which part of the Rajasthan?",
    answer: "Between Aravalli and Western Arid Zone",
    options: [
      "East of Aravalli",
      "Between Hadoti and Bhorat Plateaus",
      "Between Aravalli and Western Arid Zone",
      "In Southern Rajasthan"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 18,
    question: "The climate of India is broadly described as _______.",
    answer: "Monsoon type",
    options: [
      "Equatorial type",
      "Polar type",
      "Arid and semi-arid type",
      "Monsoon type"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which of the following places experience humid climate?",
    answer: "Kochi",
    options: [
      "Ahmedabad",
      "Kochi",
      "Ludhiana",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Which of the following does not have an influence over the climate in India ?",
    answer: "Ocean Currents",
    options: [
      "Ocean Currents",
      "Presence of Indian Ocean",
      "Monsoons",
      "Nearness to equator"
    ]
  },
];
